martinandosa.com 2008-12-17

# Martin + Osa | Help | Privacy Policy

  * United States Privacy Policy
  * California Privacy Rights
  * Canada Privacy Policy

_U.S. Privacy Policy_

American Eagle Outfitters, Inc. and its brands, which include but are not limited to American Eagle Outfitters, aerie, 77 Kids, and Martin + Osa stores or web sites (collectively, "AE"), respect your personal information and your right to privacy. We may change or add to this privacy policy at any time without notice, so we encourage you to review it periodically. AE reserves the right to vary this policy state by state as required by law. We do not sell or rent your personal information to third parties. We may share your information among our brands and, under certain circumstances, with third parties that provide services on our behalf or with whom we have partnered to offer a particular product or service. By purchasing our products or using our services or website, you consent to the collection, use and disclosure of your personal information in accordance with the following privacy policy. 

This privacy policy will tell you: 
  * What information is collected by AE
  * How we may use and share information
  * How we protect the information
  * How you may contact AE

_AE POINTS OF CONTACT_

The AE points of contact include, but are not limited to: 

  * AE stores, our AE merchandise sales websites (ae.com, aerie.com, 77kids.com, and martinandosa.com), AE's customer service line for ordering products, and communications with AE's customer relations department;
  * Any other website or on-line service that may be provided from time to time by AE or on behalf of AE such as: 
    * The customer loyalty website at aeallaccesspass.com
    * The AE Credit Card website at ae.com. This policy does not apply to information collected when you apply for an AE Credit Card (issued by GE Money Bank)
  * Mobile Devices.

_What Information Do We Collect?_ _Consumer Information_

We receive and may keep information voluntarily given to us when you decided to make an AE purchase, apply for an AE Credit Card, register on an AE website, take part in a special promotion, or provide any other information or unique preferences to better serve you. This information may include: 

  * Your name, postal address and phone number
  * Date of birth
  * Your e-mail address
  * Your mobile phone number
  * Your credit card, AE Gift Card or AE All-Access Pass Loyalty Card number
  * Proof of your identity
  * *Any other information that AE may voluntarily collect from you from time to time on its website or through alternate means. It might also include information you provide us about other people. For example, you may provide us with some of the same information as above (name and address) for a merchandise gift recipient. When you provide us with personal information about the intended recipient of a shipment, we use that information for the purposes of processing the shipment and, in some cases, to communicate with the intended recipient to provide information pertaining to the status of the shipment. We rely on you to obtain the intended recipient's consent to our use of their personal information for these limited purposes.

_Information from Other Sources_

We may receive information about you from other sources such as updated address information. This information may help us to improve our ability to serve your needs such as ensuring the accurate delivery of direct mail materials. 

_Use of Cookies and Other Technology_

We want you to be aware that certain online tools exist to help us serve and recognize you when you visit one of our websites. For your convenience, to help us personalize your experience or better serve your needs, we may receive and store certain types of information when you visit one of our websites. You may be familiar with the term "cookies." These cookies may be placed on your computer when you click on an AE e-mail, banner, or on the site directly. We use this information to understand how users navigate to and around our websites, view product pages, access content and make purchases. 

_ONCE INFORMATION IS RECEIVED, HOW IS IT USED AND/OR SHARED?_ _Within AE_

Information we collect from you may be shared between all points of contact within AE and its subsidiaries. We use this information to offer you special offers, new products, and services and may share your information with sister companies. In addition, AE may use such information to: 

  * Provide you with timely and reliable fulfillment of requests 
  * Do all things necessary to administer those services
  * Deliver merchandise and services that you purchase online
  * Register you on ae.com
  * Facilitate payment for your purchases
  * Confirm your orders and delivery information
  * Respond to your customer service inquiries or requests
  * Communicate offers, benefits and featured items to you
  * Administer giveaways, contests, birthday programs and similar promotions
  * Administer special customer recognition programs such as AE All-Access Pass
  * Find and stock the products you want
  * Customize your shopping experience and other uses as determined by AE

_Outside AE_

Certain business services are performed on AE's behalf and at AE's request by other companies. We may share your information with selected vendors that perform services for AE or to others for other marketing purposes. To perform these services, these companies may, at times, utilize some of the information you have provided AE. This information is used for the purposes AE has requested such as maintaining our database, administering and monitoring e-mails, and contest administration. aeallaccesspass.com is a limited availability website managed by our loyalty program partner. When you visit the site and choose to enter your loyalty program member number and password, our loyalty program partner receives all information on your use of the site relating specifically to this program so that they can help AE administer and manage this program. GE Money Bank manages the AE Credit Card website at ae.com. When you visit the web site, GE Money Bank receives the information you provide for the purpose of assisting AE with the administration and management of the AE Credit Card. GE Money Bank may have its own policies that govern the site when you apply for a credit card. We may also share information with governmental agencies or other companies assisting us in fraud prevention or investigation. We may do so when (1) permitted or required by law, or (2) trying to protect against or prevent actual or potential fraud or unauthorized transactions, or (3) investigating fraud that has already taken place. In addition, AE reserves the right to disclose personal information to a third party if a law, regulation, search warrant, subpoena or court order legally requires or authorizes us to do so. In all cases, this information is not provided to these entities for purposes of marketing to an AE customer. 

_Retention of Personal Information_

AE retains your personal information for as long as necessary to fulfill the purpose(s) for which it was collected and to comply with applicable laws. Your consent to such purposes(s) remains valid after any termination of our relationship with you. 

_Right to Transfer_

AE also reserves the right to disclose and/or transfer personal information to a third party in the event of a proposed or actual purchase, sale (including, but not limited to, liquidation, realization, foreclosure or repossession), lease, merger, amalgamation or any other type of acquisition, disposal, transfer, conveyance or financing of all or any portion of AE or of any of the business, assets or shares of AE or a division thereof. AE may decide to retain a copy of the information after the sale or transfer for any use. 

_HOW TO CONTACT AE_ _How do I make choices about receiving promotional communications?_

American Eagle Outfitters, Inc. and our brands, American Eagle Outfitters, aerie, 77 Kids, and Martin + Osa, want to communicate with you only if you want to hear from us. If you prefer not to receive promotional information, such as information about special offers and sales events, from one or more of our brands, you can let us know by contacting our customer service via telephone, postal mail, e-mail or through an AE brand website as described below. 

When contacting customer service, please be sure to include your full name and the email address you used when you registered with or made a purchase from the AE brand. If you ask us to remove your name and address from promotional lists, we will maintain your name in a "do not contact" file to ensure that we can honor your request. It may take up to 10 days to process your email request and 6-8 weeks to process your postal mail request, during which period you may continue to receive communications from AE. 

If you change your mind, you can start receiving promotional communications from us again by logging into your online account and changing your preferences, by signing up when you visit our websites or our stores or when you enter a sweepstakes or contest, or by contacting customer service. Please note that when you make an online purchase from us, we will continue to confirm your order status and shipment by email. We may also need to contact you via telephone, email or postal mail with questions or information regarding your order. 

_Postal Mail_

If you do not want to receive promotional mail from AE via postal service, send a letter stating this with your name and address to [custserv@ae.com](mailto:custserv@ae.com "Customer Service"), or to our mailing address below. You can also call us at 1-888-232-4535 with your request. 

_E-mails_

When you fill out one of our forms or other requests for information, you may choose to receive e-mail that informs you about new merchandise in our stores or online, as well as special offers and promotions. In addition, we may send you e-mails to help us learn more about you and your preferences. If, after you have shared your e-mail address with AE, you decide that you do not want to receive e-mail from AE, you have several options to let us know of your preferences: 

  * You can go to ae.com, access your AE Account profile, uncheck the box marked "Send me e-mails with ae.com promotions" and follow the instructions
  * If you are a participant in our customer loyalty program, call 1-800-340-0532
  * You can discontinue promotional e-mails by clicking on the hyperlink shown in all AE e-mails and follow the instructions to indicate your unsubscribe preference
  * Contact AE customer relations 

As it relates to questions you might have about our Privacy Policy or if you have a concern that AE may have failed to adhere to this Privacy Policy, please call customer relations at 1-888-232-4535, e-mail [custserv@ae.com](mailto:custserv@ae.com "Customer Service"), or write us as follows: 

_Text Messaging_

Customers may decide to have marketing messages sent directly to their mobile devices via text messaging. This program is completely voluntary, and messages will only be sent to customers who have asked to receive them. If you have errantly received a marketing text message without opting in to the program, or if you wish to opt out of receiving messages, please respond to the text message in the following manner: 

  * For AEO, reply to the message with "eagleout"
  * For aerie, reply to the message with "aerieout"
  * For 77 Kids, reply to the message with "77kidsout" and
  * For M+O, reply to the message with "mandoout"

Standard text messaging & other charges may apply. Please consult the applicable wireless service agreement for your individual pricing plan. 

You can reach customer support via email at [mobile@ae.com](mailto:mobile@ae.com) or via phone at 888.232.4535 

Please note that it may take up to 10 days to process your stop request, during which time you may receive additional text messages from AE. 

American Eagle Outfitters, Inc.

77 Hot Metal St.

Pittsburgh, PA 15203

Attention: Director of CRM

You may also contact us in any one of the above ways to request access to or correction or update of your personal information. 

If you have specific questions regarding your AE Credit Card, you can call AE Credit Card Customer Service at 1-800-843-0875 during the Eastern U.S. time zone hours of 8 a.m. - 12 midnight Monday - Saturday or 9 a.m. - 10 p.m. on Sunday. You can also write to: 

American Eagle Outfitters Credit Card

P.O. Box 530993

Atlanta, GA 30353-0993

_Miscellaneous_ _Our Policy on gathering information from and communicating with children online_

We recognize the unique privacy issues regarding children, and share parents? concerns for their security and safety. Our websites are intended for a general audience, and we do not directly market to children under the age of 13. Furthermore, Pursuant to COPPA guidelines, we do not knowingly collect or store personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13 absent prior verifiable parental consent. If a parent or guardian is made aware that a child under the age of 13 has provided us with personally identifiable information without their consent, please contact us at 1-888-232-4535, by e-mail at [custserv@ae.com](mailto:custserv@ae.com "Customer Service"), or at the address listed above, and we will remove the information about the individual from our marketing database. 

77 Kids cannot and will not condition a child?s participation in any activity on the unnecessary disclosure of the child?s personal information. 77 Kids shares a child?s personal information with third parties only in the following circumstances: 

  * When disclosure is reasonably necessary to comply with law;
  * When the disclosure is necessary to protect the security of the web site;
  * When the disclosure is necessary to comply with website and/or sweepstakes rules.

77 Kids may share information with business partners, who are contractually bound to maintain the confidentiality, integrity, and security of that information. The sharing of information with business partners is done only to allow for their assistance in already consented-to activities (e.g. the fulfillment of order requests, website services, or sweepstakes facilitation). 

_Our Commitment to Data Security_

AE makes commercially reasonable efforts to ensure that personal information collected from you is protected against loss and unauthorized access. This protection applies in relation to information stored in both electronic and hard copy form. AE uses industry standard security techniques on our websites to help protect against the loss, misuse or modification of information that you have provided. When you access your personal information or transmit personally identifiable data to us, that information is stored on servers that we have used commercially reasonable efforts to protect from unauthorized access or intrusion. While we implement the above security measures, you should be aware that 100% security is not possible. 

_Know How to Identify American Eagle Outfitters Email_

To help you protect your information, we will never ask for the following: 
  * We will never send you an email asking you to verify financial account or credit card account information.
  * We will never send you an email requesting personal information such as passwords, social security number, driver's license number or your mother's maiden name.
  * We will never send you an email that threatens to terminate your account.

_If Emails Look Suspicious_

  * If you receive a suspected fraudulent email that makes use of the American Eagle Outfitters name, please forward it to us at custserv@ae.com or call us at 1-888-307-3672.
  * To ensure you reach American Eagle Outfitter's website, we ask you to type any website address we provide into the address line of your browser. This prevents you from being inadvertently redirected to a different website.

_What happens if I hit a link to another site from an AE site?_

Our websites may offer links to other sites. Other sites have their own terms of use and privacy and security policies. AE is not responsible for how such third parties collect, use or disclose your personal information. If you choose to visit one of these sites, you may want to review the policies that govern that particular site. 

_Your California Privacy Rights_

This supplements the US Privacy Policy. 

Beginning January 1, 2005, under California's "Shine the Light" law, California residents who provide personal information in obtaining products or services for personal, family or household use are entitled to request and obtain from us once a calendar year information about the customer information we shared, if any, with other businesses for their own direct marketing uses. If applicable, this information would include the categories of customer information and the names and addresses of those businesses with which we shared customer information for the immediately prior calendar year (e.g., requests made in 2005 will receive information regarding 2004 sharing activities). To obtain this information, please send an e-mail message to [customerservice@martinandosa.com](mailto:customerservice@martinandosa.com "Customer Service") with "Request for California Privacy Information" on the subject line and in the body of your message. We will provide the requested information to you at your e-mail address in response. Please be aware that not all information sharing is covered by the "Shine the Light" requirements and only information on covered sharing will be included in our response. 

_Canada Privacy Policy_

American Eagle Outfitters, Inc. ("AEO") and its subsidiaries, including Martin + Osa, respect your right to privacy. We may change or add to this privacy policy at any time without notice, so we encourage you to review it periodically. Martin + Osa reserves the right to vary this policy state by state as required by law. By purchasing our products or using our services or website, you consent to the collection, use and disclosure of your personal information in accordance with the following privacy policy. 

This privacy policy will tell you: 

  * What information is collected by Martin + Osa
  * How we may use and share information
  * How we protect the information
  * How you may contact Martin + Osa
  * Martin + Osa POINTS OF CONTACT

_Martin + Osa Points of Contact_

The Martin + Osa points of contact include, but are not limited to: Martin + Osa stores, our merchandise sales website martinandosa.com, Martin + Osa's customer service line for ordering products, and communications with Martin + Osa's customer relations department; Any other website or on-line service that may be provided from time to time by Martin + Osa or on behalf of Martin + Osa such as: 

  * American Eagle Outfitters and martinandosa.com

_What Information Do We Collect?_ _Consumer Information_

We receive and may keep information voluntarily given to us when you decided to make a Martin + Osa purchase, register on a Martin + Osa website, take part in a special promotion, or provide any other information or unique preferences to better serve you. This information may include: 

  * Your name, address and phone number
  * Date of birth
  * Your e-mail address
  * Your credit card or Martin + Osa Gift Card
  * Proof of your identity
  * Any other information that Martin + Osa may voluntarily collect from you from time to time on its website or through alternate means

It might also include information you provide us about other people. For example, you may provide us with some of the same information as above (name and address) for a merchandise gift recipient. When you provide us with personal information about the intended recipient of a shipment, we use that information for the purposes of processing the shipment and, in some cases, to communicate with the intended recipient to provide information pertaining to the status of the shipment. We rely on you to obtain the intended recipient's consent to our use of their personal information for these limited purposes. 

_Information from Other Sources_

We may receive information about you from other sources such as updated address information. This information may help us to improve our ability to serve your needs such as ensuring the accurate delivery of direct mail materials. 

_Use of Cookies and Other Technology_

We want you to be aware that certain online tools exist to help us serve and recognize you when you visit one of our websites. For your convenience, to help us personalize your experience or better serve your needs, we may receive and store certain types of information when you visit one of our websites. You may be familiar with the term "cookies." These cookies may be placed on your computer when you click on a Martin + Osa e-mail, banner, or on the site directly. We use this information to understand how users navigate to and around our websites, view product pages, access content and make purchases. 

_Once Information is Received, How is it used and/or shared?_ _Within AEO, Inc._

Information we collect from you may be shared between all points of contact within AEO, Inc. and its subsidiaries. We use this information to offer you special offers, new products, and services and may share your information with sister companies. In addition, Martin + Osa may use such information to: 

  * Provide you with timely and reliable fulfillment of requests
  * Do all things necessary to administer those services
  * Deliver merchandise and services that you purchase online
  * Register you on martinandosa.com
  * Facilitate payment for your purchases
  * Confirm your orders and delivery information
  * Respond to your customer service inquiries or requests
  * Communicate offers, benefits and featured items to you
  * Administer giveaways, contests, birthday programs and similar promotions
  * Administer special customer recognition programs
  * Find and stock the products you want
  * Customize your shopping experience and other uses as determined by Martin + Osa

_Outside Martin + Osa_

Certain business services are performed on Martin + Osa's behalf and at Martin + Osa's request by other companies. We may share your information with selected vendors that perform services for Martin + Osa or to others for other marketing purposes. To perform these services, these companies may, at times, utilize some of the information you have provided Martin + Osa. This information is used for the purposes Martin + Osa has requested such as maintaining our database, administering and monitoring e-mails, and contest administration. We may also share information with governmental agencies or other companies assisting us in fraud prevention or investigation. We may do so when (1) permitted or required by law, or (2) trying to protect against or prevent actual or potential fraud or unauthorized transactions, or (3) investigating fraud that has already taken place. In addition, Martin + Osa reserves the right to disclose personal information to a third party if a law, regulation, search warrant, subpoena or court order legally requires or authorizes us to do so. In all cases, this information is not provided to these entities for purposes of marketing to a Martin + Osa customer. 

_Retention of Personal Information_

Martin + Osa retains your personal information for as long as necessary to fulfill the purpose(s) for which it was collected and to comply with applicable laws. Your consent to such purposes(s) remains valid after any termination of our relationship with you. 

_Right to Transfer_

Martin + Osa also reserves the right to disclose and/or transfer personal information to a third party in the event of a proposed or actual purchase, sale (including, but not limited to, liquidation, realization, foreclosure or repossession), lease, merger, amalgamation or any other type of acquisition, disposal, transfer, conveyance or financing of all or any portion of Martin + Osa or of any of the business, assets or shares of Martin + Osa or a division thereof. Martin + Osa may decide to retain a copy of the information after the sale or transfer for any use. 

_How to Contact Martin + Osa_ _Postal Mail_

If you do not want to receive promotional mail from Martin + Osa via postal service, send a letter stating this with your name and address to [customerservice@martinandosa.com](mailto:customerservice@martinandosa.com "Customer Service"), or to our mailing address below. You can also call us at 1.800.227.2439 with your request. 

_E-mails_

When you fill out one of our forms or other requests for information, you may choose to receive e-mail that informs you about new merchandise in our stores or online, as well as special offers and promotions. In addition, we may send you e-mails to help us learn more about you and your preferences. If, after you have shared your e-mail address with Martin + Osa, you decide that you do not want to receive e-mail from Martin + Osa, you have several options to let us know of your preferences: 

  * You can go to martinandosa.com, access your Martin + Osa Account profile, uncheck the box marked "Send me e-mails with martinandosa.com promotions" and follow the instructions
  * You can discontinue promotional e-mails by clicking on the hyperlink shown in all Martin + Osa e-mails and follow the instructions to indicate your unsubscribe preference
  * Contact Martin + Osa customer relations as set forth below

As it relates to questions you might have about our Privacy Policy or if you have a concern that Martin + Osa may have failed to adhere to this Privacy Policy, please call customer relations at 1.800.227.2439, e-mail [customerservice@martinandosa.com](mailto:customerservice@martinandosa.com "Customer Service"), or write us as follows: 

Martin + Osa

Attention: Senior Director of CRM

c/o Customer Relations

150 Thorn Hill Road 

Warrendale, PA 15086

You may also contact us in any one of the above ways to request access to or correction or update of your personal information. 

_MISCELLANEOUS_ _Our Policy on gathering information from and communicating with children online_

We recognize the unique privacy concerns regarding children. Pursuant to COPPA guidelines, we do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information online from children under the age of 13. If a parent or guardian is made aware that a child under the age of 13 has provided us with personally identifiable information without their consent, please contact us at 1.800.227.2439, by e-mail at [customerservice@martinandosa.com](mailto:customerservice@martinandosa.com "Customer Service"), or at the address listed above, and we will remove the information about the individual from our marketing database. 

_Our Commitment to Data Security_

Martin + Osa makes commercially reasonable efforts to ensure that personal information collected from you is protected against loss and unauthorized access. This protection applies in relation to information stored in both electronic and hard copy form. Martin + Osa uses industry standard security techniques on our websites to help protect against the loss, misuse or modification of information that you have provided. When you access your personal information or transmit personally identifiable data to us, that information is stored on servers that we have used commercially reasonable efforts to protect from unauthorized access or intrusion. While we implement the above security measures, you should be aware that 100% security is not possible. 

_Know How to Identify Martin + Osa Email_

To help you protect your information, we will never ask for the following: 

  * We will never send you an email asking you to verify financial account or credit card account information.
  * We will never send you an email requesting personal information such as passwords, social security number, driver's license number or your mother's maiden name.
  * We will never send you an email that threatens to terminate your account.

_If Emails Look Suspicious_

If you receive a suspected fraudulent email that makes use of the Martin + Osa name, please forward it to us at [customerservice@martinandosa.com](mailto:customerservice@martinandosa.com "Customer Service") or call us at 1.800.227.2439. To ensure you reach Martin + Osa's website, we ask you to type any website address we provide into the address line of your browser. This prevents you from being inadvertently redirected to a different website. 

_What happens if I hit a link to another site from a Martin + Osa site?_

Our websites may offer links to other sites. Other sites have their own terms of use and privacy and security policies. Martin + Osa is not responsible for how such third parties collect, use or disclose your personal information. If you choose to visit one of these sites, you may want to review the policies that govern that particular site.
